Register of the Russia. Posol'stvo (U.S.) Records, 1897-1947.
Hoover Institution Archives
- Subject File, 1897-1947.
  - Subagencies
    - Russian Supply Committee. (see also Subject File/ Russian Volunteer Fleet/1918/January-April)
      - General (Folder 10)
      - Baldin, M. A. (Folder 11)
      - Gaiduk, Moisei, Utiug, New York, 1918 (Folder 12)
  - Trotskii, Lev--see Russia/General, 1920 and 1921
  - Turkey. (see also Refugees, Russian/Turkey and Serbia) (Folder 13)
  - Union of Soviet Socialist Republics--see Russia
  - United States
    - Left wing movements in the--see Subject File/Sub- agencies/Consulates/Left wing movements in North America
    - Russia, Relations with
      - General--see Subject File/Allied policies towards Russia; and Subject/File/Martens, L.
      - American private relief organizations--see Subject File/Russia/Famine -- American private relief organizations
      - American Relief Administration--see Subject File/ Russia/Revolution, 1917-1921/Counterrevolution- ary movements/Supplies from abroad
  - Yugoslavia--see Refugees, Russian/Turkey and Serbia; and Slavs
- Consulate General, Montreal Office File, 1917-1920.
  Available on microfilm reels 46-55
  Account books, affidavits, bank statements, checkbooks, checkstubs, clippings, correspondence, lists of depositors and remitters, memoranda, notes, passbooks, receipts, reports, statements of accounts, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Budget (Box 40, Folder 1)
    Available on microfilm reel 46
  - Financial transaction -- transfer of securities to Sergei Uget (Folder 2)
  - Russian Consulate, Vancouver (Folder 3)
  - Russian savings banks
    - General
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Correspondence
        - Bank of Montreal--see Private persons and organizations
        - Great North Western Telegraph Company of Canada, Montreal--see Private persons and organizations
        - Main Administration of Russian Savings Banks, Petrograd, Omsk--see Russian state agencies
        - National City Bank of New York--see Private persons and organizations
        - National Trust Company--see Private persons and organizations
        - Novitskii, Vladimir--see Russian state agencies
        - Private persons and organizations
          - A-C (Folder 5)
          - D (Folder 6)
          - E-G (Folder 7)
          - I-K (Folder 8)
          - L (Box 41, Folder 1)
            Available on microfilm reel 47
          - M-O (Folder 2)
          - P-S (Folder 3)
          - T-Z (Folder 4)
        - Russian state agencies
          - 1918 (Folder 5)
          - 1918-1919 (Folder 6)
            Available on microfilm reel 48
          - 1919 (Box 42, Folder 1)
          - 1920 (Folder 2)
        - Ter-Asaturov, Dmitrii--see Russian state agencies
        - Uget, Sergei--see Russian state agencies
      - Reports
        - 1917-1918
          - Report (Folder 3)
          - Appendix (Folder 4)
            Available on microfilm reel 49
        - 1918
          - January-April
            - Report (Folder 5)
            - Appendix (Folder 6)
          - May-August (Folder 7)
          - May-December (Folder 8)
          - September-December (Box 43, Folder 1)
        - 1919
          - January-April (Folder 2)
            Available on microfilm reel 50
          - May-August
            - General (Folder 3)
            - Special (Folder 4)
          - September-December (Folder 5)
        - 1920 (Box 44, Folder 1)
  - Russian savings banks (Contd.)
    - Bank of Montreal
      - Account books
        - Accounts 2 & 3 (Folder 2)
          Available on microfilm reel 51
        - Accounts 4 & 5 (Folder 3)
      - Checkstubs
        - Account 2 (Folder 4)
        - Account 3 (Folder 5)
        - Account 4 (Folder 6)
      - Statements of accounts (Folder 7)
    - Bel'skii, Boris (Box 45, Folder 1)
    - Karpovich, Petr (Folder 2)
    - Office supply (Folder 3-4)
    - Refunds to Russian depositors and remitters
      - Deposits
        - Lists of depositors
          - 1918 (Folder 5)
          - 1919 (Folder 6)
          - 1920 (Folder 7)
        - Passbooks
          - 1918 (Folder 8)
          - 1918-1919 (Folder 9)
            Available on microfilm reel 52
          - 1919 (Box 46, Folder 1)
          - 1920 (Folder 2)
            - January-April (Folder 3)
            - May-August
        - Statements--see Passbooks
      - Deposits and transfers
        - 1918-1920 (Folder 4)
          Available on microfilm reel 53
        - 1920 (Box 47)
          - February (Folder 1)
          - March (Folder 2)
          - March-September (Folder 3)
          - April (Folder 4)
            Available on microfilm reel 54
          - May (Folder 5)
          - June (Folder 6)
          - July (Box 48, Folder 1)
          - August (Folder 2)
      - Transfers. (see also Deposits and transfers)
        - Affidavits, 1920
          - March (Folder 3)
            Not available on microfilm
          - March (Box 49, Folder 1)
          - April (Box 50, Folder 1)
          - May (Folder 2)
          - June (Box 51, Folder 1)
          - July (Folder 2)
          - August (Folder 3)
        - Checks--see Affidavits
        - Lists of remitters
          - Not refunded (Folder 4)
          - Refunded (Folder 5)
        - Receipts. (see also Affidavits)
          - Addressees (Folder 6)
          - Main Administration of Russian Savings Banks (Folder 7)
    - Russian State Control (Folder 8)
    - Sosnovskii, Sigizmund (Folder 9)
  - Uget, Sergei--see Financial transaction -- transfer of securities to Sergei Uget.
- Division of Supplies Office File, 1918-1920.
  Available on microfilm reels 55-121
  Administrative orders, affidavits, correspondence, diagrams, financial records, memoranda, receipts, reports, tables, arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - Anglo-Russian Subcommittee (Box 52, Folder 1)
    Available on microfilm reel 55
  - Artillery Section (Folder 2)
  - Commissariat Section (Folder 3)
  - Commission on the Russian Freighters Returned by the United States Shipping Board (Folder 4)
  - Financial Section
    - General
      - Affidavit (Folder 5)
      - Clippings (Folder 6)
      - Correspondence
        - Secret
          - Letters
            - 1919 (Folder 7)
            - 1920 (Folder 8)
          - Register (Folder 9)
        - Solicitation letters (Folder 10)
        - Zamen, Konrad (Folder 11)
          Available on microfilm reel 56
      - Financial records (Box 53)
        - General
          - n.d. (Folder 1)
          - 1917-1918 (Folder 2)
          - 1918-1920 (Folder 3)
          - 1919
            - January-June (Folder 4)
            - June-December (Folder 5)
          - 1919-1920 (Folder 6-7)
            Available on microfilm reel 57
          - 1920
            - March-April (Folder 8)
            - May-October (Folder 9)
            - September-October (Folder 10)
        - Bank statements (Box 54)
          - 1918 (Folder 1)
          - 1919 (Folder 2)
          - 1919-1920 (Folder 3)
        - Checkstubs
          - 1918 (Folder 4)
            Available on microfilm reel 58
          - 1918-1919 (Folder 5)
          - 1919-1920 (Folder 6)
          - 1920 (Folder 7)
        - Credit books
          - 1918 (Folder 8)
          - 1919 (Box 55, Folder 1)
          - 1920 (Folder 2-3)
      - Orders (Box 56, Folder 1)
    - Account Subdivision (Folder 2)
      Available on microfilm reel 59
    - American Bank Note Company, New York
      - General
        - 1918 (Folder 3)
        - 1919 (Folder 4)
        - 1919-1920 (Folder 5)
      - Internal 4 1/2% loan (Folder 6)
      - Shipment of banknotes to Crimea (Folder 7)
    - American Can Company, New York (Folder 8)
    - American Red Cross (Folder 9)
    - Bear Lithia Springs Company, New York (Folder 10)
    - Black Tom Island Explosion (Folder 11)
    - Bogoslov Mining Company (Folder 12)
    - Borodin, Nikolai, Representative of the Russian Ministry of Agriculture, Omsk (Folder 13)
      Available on microfilm reel 60
    - Canadian Pacific Railway Company--see Freighters/Key West
    - Central Russian Fourth Liberty Committee (Folder 14)
    - Chinese Eastern Railway--see Ivan Stakheev & Company
    - Commerical products (Box 57)
      - General (Folder 1)
      - Automobiles (Folder 2)
      - Coal (Folder 3)
      - Exchanges (Folder 4)
      - Locomotives (Folder 5)
      - Military shoes (Folder 6)
      - Rifles and cartridges (Folder 7)
      - Sole leather
        - General (Folder 8)
          Available on microfilm reel 61
        - Czechoslovak army in Russia (Folder 9)
      - Warehouses in Vladivostok and Arkhangel'sk (Folder 10)
    - Division of Supplies
      - All-Russian Zemstvos and Cities' Union. American Commission (Folder 11)
      - Budget (Folder 12)
      - Commissariat Section (Folder 13)
      - Commission for Reviewing Petitions for Money Allowances (Folder 14)
      - General Chancery (Box 58, Folder 1)
      - Machinery Section (Folder 2)
      - Mission of Ways of Communication
        - Budget (Folder 3)
          Available on microfilm reel 62
        - Commercial products (Folder 4)
        - Personnel (Folder 5)
      - Naval Section (Folder 6)
      - Russian Remington Rifle Contract Trustee
        - General (Folder 7-9)
        - Barrow Wade Guthrie & Company, Philadelphia (Folder 10)
        - Budget (Folder 11)
        - Cartridges (Folder 12)
        - Claims (Folder 13)
        - Committee for Assuming Control by the Russian Government of the Supplies and Materials at the Remington Plant (Folder 14)
        - Credit of 29 April 1919 (Folder 15)
        - Gold deposit at the Hongkong & Shanghai Banking Corporation (Box 59)
          - 1919-1920 (Folder 1)
            Available on microfilm reel 63
          - 1920 (Folder 2)
        - Rifles
          - General
            - 1918 (Folder 3)
            - 1918-1919 (Folder 4)
            - 1920 (Folder 5)
              Available on microfilm reel 64
          - Shipment to Seattle (Folder 6)
          - Storage fee (Folder 7)
        - Russian State Control (Folder 8)
      - Transportation and Warehouse Section
        - Correspondence
          - 1919 (Folder 9)
          - 1919-1920 (Folder 10)
        - Financial records (Box 60)
          - 1918-1919 (Folder 1-2)
          - 1919 (Folder 3)
    - Eitington Schild Company, New York
      - 1919
        - June-December (Folder 4)
        - July-December (Folder 5)
      - 1919-1920 (Folder 6)
        Available on microfilm reel 65
    - Fabian, Konstantin
      - 1918-1919 (Folder 7)
      - 1919-1920 (Folder 8)
    - Freighters
      - Anna-Sofia (Folder 9)
      - Eastern Victor (Folder 10)
      - Faraby (Box 61, Folder 1)
      - Frederick (Folder 2)
      - Indigirka and Simbirsk (Folder 3)
      - Key West (Folder 4)
      - Rogdai (Folder 5)
    - Gaston, Williams and Wigmore, Inc. (Folder 6)
      Available on microfilm reel 66
    - Great Britain--see Seizure of the Russian cargoes by the British Government
    - Gudkov, Valentin. (see also Bogoslov Mining Company) (Folder 7)
    - Hamilton and Hansel, Inc., New York
      - 1918 (Folder 8)
      - 1918-1919 (Folder 9)
      - 1919-1920 (Folder 10)
    - Holbrook, Cabot & Rollins Corporation (Folder 11)
    - Holmes Electric Protective Company (Folder 12)
    - International Finance (Box 62)
      - General (Folder 1)
      - Loan to the All-Russian Government in Omsk (Folder 2)
        Available on microfilm reel 67
    - Ivan Stakheev and Company (Folder 3)
    - Korf, Oskar (Folder 4)
    - Lomonosov, Iurii
      - 1918 (Folder 5)
      - 1918-1920 (Folder 6)
    - Marine Transport Service Corporation (Folder 7)
    - Maryland Casualty Company, Baltimore (Folder 8)
    - Morozov, Petr (Folder 9)
    - Moscow District Supply Committee--Fabian, Konstantin
    - Moscow Machine Tool and Engine Company (Folder 10)
    - Novitskii, Vladimir
      - 1919 (Folder 11)
      - 1919-1920 (Folder 12-13)
      - 1920 (Box 63, Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 68
    - People's Industrial Trading Corporation, New York, 1919
      - August-September (Folder 2)
      - September-November (Folder 3)
      - November-December (Folder 4)
    - Pertsov, Dmitrii. Reports
      - General (Folder 5)
      - "Proekt organizatsii v Amerike 'Emigratsionnogo banka'" (Folder 6-7)
    - Plym & Ochs, Ltd., New York (Folder 8)
    - Poluboiarinov, Aleksandr (Box 64)
      - Biographical file (Folder 1)
        Available on microfilm reel 69
      - "Moia predvaritel'naia zapiska" -- memorandum on Russian finance, 16 July 1918 (Folder 2)
      - "Zapiska o vvedenii novykh denezhnykh znakov v sviazi s pomoshch'iu soiuznykh derzhav," 26 July 1918
        - Correspondence (Folder 3)
        - Holograph (Folder 4)
        - Typewritten copy (Folder 5)
      - "Some Considerations with Reference to the Memorandum of August 1918 Concerning the Mode of Payment in Russia," 6 September 1918 (Folder 6)
    - Refugees, Russian
      - Organizations (Folder 7)
      - Petrograd Loan Fisc (Folder 8)
      - Relief (Folder 9)
      - Veterans (Folder 10)
    - Remington Arms Union Metallic Cartridge Company. (see also Division of Supplies/Russian Remington Rifle Contract Trustee) (Folder 11)
    - Rumania--see Commercial products/Locomotives
    - Russia/Revolution, 1917-1921/Counterrevolutionary movements
      - North--see Financial Section/American Red Cross; Financial Section/Commercial products/Coal; Financial Section/Novitskii, Vladimir
      - Siberia and Far East--see Financial Section/ Commercial products/Exchanges; Financial Section/Eitington Schild Company; Financial Section/Novitskii, Vladimir
      - South--see Financial Section/Morozov, Petr
    - Russian banknotes
      - 1918-1919 (Folder 12)
        Available on microfilm reel 70
      - 1918-1920 (Folder 13)
    - Russian church
      - 1919-1920 (Folder 14)
      - 1920 (Folder 15)
    - Russian commerce
      - General (Folder 16)
      - Canada, with (Box 65)
        - Correspondence (Folder 1)
        - Tables (Folder 2)
      - United States, with the (Folder 3)
    - Russian deposits in the National City Bank of New York
      - General (Folder 4)
      - Compt' Tr'sor S'par' Account (Folder 5)
    - Russian Embassy, Washington
      - Consulates
        - Budget
          - 1919-1920 (Folder 6)
          - 1920 (Folder 7)
        - Savings banks
          - General
            - 1918-1920 (Folder 8)
              Available on microfilm reel 71
            - 1920 (Folder 9)
          - Chicago
            - 1918-1920 (Folder 10)
            - 1920 (Box 66)
              - March-June (Folder 1)
              - June-December (Folder 2)
          - Montreal
            - 1918-1919 (Folder 3)
            - 1919 (Folder 4)
              Available on microfilm reel 72
            - 1919-1920 (Folder 5)
            - 1920
              - March-July (Folder 6)
              - August-September (Box 67, Folder 1)
              - September-October (Folder 2)
          - New York
            - 1918-1919 (Folder 3)
            - 1919 (Folder 4)
              Available on microfilm reel 73
            - 1919-1920 (Folder 5)
            - 1920 (Folder 6)
          - Novitskii, Vladimir (Folder 7)
          - Pittsburgh
            - 1918-1920 (Folder 8)
            - 1920
              - March-June (Folder 9)
              - August-October (Folder 10)
          - Seattle (Folder 11)
            Available on microfilm reel 74
      - Military agent (Box 68, Folder 1)
      - Petrograd Zemstvos and Cities Regional Committee Army Supply (Folder 2)
      - Russian State Control
        - 1918-1919
          - Correspondence (Folder 3)
          - Receipts (Folder 4)
        - 1918-1920 (Folder 5)
        - 1919-1920 (Folder 6-7)
        - 1920 (Folder 8)
      - Russian Supply Committee (Folder 9)
    - Russian Information Bureau, New York (Folder 10)
    - Russian missions and legations -- South America (Folder 11)
    - Russian nationals in the United States -- money remittances to Russia
      - Private banks (Folder 12)
      - Russian State Savings Bank -- Project (Folder 13)
        Available on microfilm reel 75
    - Russian Provisional Government -- debts in the United States (Folder 14)
    - Russian Red Cross (Folder 15)
    - Russian Volunteer Fleet
      - 1918 (Folder 16)
      - 1918-1920 (Folder 17)
      - 1919-1920 (Folder 18)
    - Seizure of the Russian cargoes by the British Government (Box 69)
      - General
        - Correspondence
          - General
            - 1919 (Folder 1)
            - 1919-1920 (Folder 2-3)
              Available on microfilm reel 76
          - U.S. Treasury Department, 1920
            - January-March (Folder 4)
            - April-November (Folder 5)
        - Inventories
          - General (Folder 6)
            - Great Britain, in
              - Dora (Folder 7)
              - Oconee (Folder 8)
              - Vologda (Folder 9)
            - Japan, in (Folder 10)
        - Report on Investigation into Russian cargo (Box 70, Folder 1)
          Available on microfilm reel 77
      - Settlement of claims
        - Dora (Folder 2)
        - Dora, Oconee, Pawnee, Vologda (Folder 3-4)
        - Dora, Pawnee, Vologda (Folder 5)
        - Dora, Vologda (Folder 6)
        - Pawnee, Vologda
          - General Electric Co., New York (Folder 7)
          - Worthington Pump and Machinery Corporation (Folder 8)
        - Vologda
          - Berg, Abraham (Folder 9)
          - Davies Turner Co.--see Treugol'nik, Russian American India Rubber Company
          - Gerhard & Hey, Inc. (Folder 10)
          - Ingersol Rand Company, New York (Folder 11)
          - Iznosskoff & Company, Petrograd
            - 1918-1919 (Folder 12)
            - 1919-1920 (Folder 13)
              Available on microfilm reel 78
            - 1920 (Box 71, Folder 1)
          - John MacGregor Grant, Inc., New York
            - 1919-1920 (Folder 2)
            - 1920 (Folder 3)
          - Lowener, V., New York (Folder 4)
          - Renault Selling Branch, Inc., New York (Folder 5)
          - Richards, C. B. & Company (Folder 6)
          - Russo-Baltic Car Works Company (Folder 7)
          - Treugol'nik, Russian American India Rubber Company (Folder 8)
    - Semenovskii, Apollinarii (Folder 9)
    - Shumatov, L. A. (Folder 10)
    - Sobanskii, Viacheslav (Folder 11)
    - Tennessee Copper Company
      - 1918-1919 (Folder 12)
        Available on microfilm reel 79
      - 1919-1920 (Folder 13)
    - Ter-Asaturov, Dmitrii (Box 72)
      - General
        - Correspondence
          - 1918-1920 (Folder 1-2)
          - 1920 (Folder 3)
        - Daily file
          - 1919
            - April-July (Folder 4)
            - August-October (Folder 5)
            - November-December (Folder 6)
              Available on microfilm reel 80
          - 1920
            - January-February (Folder 7)
            - March-April (Folder 8)
            - May-July (Folder 9)
            - August-September (Box 73, Folder 1)
            - September-October (Folder 2)
              Available on microfilm reel 81
        - Orders (Folder 3)
      - Business trip to Seattle (Folder 4)
      - National City Bank of New York (Folder 5)
      - "Operatsii rossiiskikh gosudarstvennykh sberegatel'nykh kass pri rossiiskikh konsul'stvakh v Amerike." Typewritten copy (Folder 6)
      - Platinum market in the United States (Folder 7)
      - Russian finance
        - General (Folder 8)
        - American credits (Folder 9)
          Available on microfilm reel 82
    - Uget, Sergei
      - General
        - Correspondence
          - 1918-1920 (Folder 10-11)
          - 1919-1920 (Folder 12)
        - Daily file, 1920 (Box 74)
          - January
            - 1-7 (Folder 1)
            - 8-12 (Folder 2)
            - 12-16 (Folder 3)
            - 17-21 (Folder 4)
              Available on microfilm reel 83
            - 21-26 (Folder 5)
          - January-February (Folder 6)
          - February
            - 2-7 (Folder 7)
            - 9-11 (Folder 8)
            - 13-19 (Box 75, Folder 1)
              Available on microfilm reel 84
            - 20-25 (Folder 2)
            - 25-27 (Folder 3)
          - February-March (Folder 4)
          - March
            - 6-13 (Folder 5)
            - 13-17 (Folder 6)
              Available on microfilm reel 85
            - 17-24 (Folder 7)
            - 24-29 (Folder 8)
          - March-April (Box 76, Folder 1)
          - April
            - 5-8 (Folder 2)
            - 8-14 (Folder 3)
              Available on microfilm reel 86
            - 14-21 (Folder 4)
            - 20-26 (Folder 5)
          - April-May (Folder 6)
          - May
            - 4-10 (Folder 7)
            - 10-14 (Folder 8)
              Available on microfilm reel 87
            - 13-20 (Box 77, Folder 1)
            - 20-26 (Folder 2)
          - May-June (Folder 3)
          - June
            - 2-14 (Folder 4)
            - 14-21 (Folder 5)
              Available on microfilm reel 88
            - 21-30 (Folder 6)
          - June-July (Folder 7)
          - July
            - 9-16 (Folder 8)
            - 16-26 (Box 78, Folder 1)
          - July-August (Folder 2)
            Available on microfilm reel 89
          - August
            - 3-10 (Folder 3)
            - 10-14 (Folder 4)
            - 13-21 (Folder 5)
            - 21-27 (Folder 6)
            - 27-30 (Folder 7)
              Available on microfilm reel 90
          - September
            - 1-11 (Folder 8)
            - 11-20 (Box 79, Folder 1)
            - 20-28 (Folder 2)
          - September-October (Folder 3)
          - October
            - 7-18 (Folder 4)
              Available on microfilm reel 91
            - 18-20 (Folder 5)
            - 20-30 (Folder 6)
      - Business trip to Europe, 1920
        - May (Folder 7)
        - May-August (Folder 8)
    - Union of Siberian Creamery Associations (Box 80, Folder 1)
      Available on microfilm reel 92
    - United States
      - Economic condition--see International finance
      - Treasury Department--see Financial Section/ Semenovskii, Apollinarii
    - Western Cartridge Company, East Alton, Illinois (Folder 2)
    - Western Union Telegraph Company
      - 1919-1920 (Folder 3-4)
      - 1920 (Folder 5)
    - William and Smith Company, New York (Folder 6)
    - Zamen, Konrad--see Novitskii, Vladimir/1919-1920
  - General Chancery
    - General
      - Correspondence
        - General
          - Covering letters (Folder 7)
          - Secret (Folder 8)
        - Coudert Brothers (Folder 9)
      - Diagrams (Folder 10)
      - Financial records
        - General (Folder 11)
        - Account book (Folder 12)
      - Orders (Box 81)
        - 1918 (Folder 1-2)
          Available on microfilm reel 93
        - 1919 (Folder 3-4)
    - American Locomotive Company, Paterson, New Jersey (Folder 5)
    - American Red Cross (Folder 6)
    - Archives
      - General
        - 1918 (Folder 7)
        - 1918-1919 (Folder 8)
      - Canadian Car and Foundry Company (Folder 9)
      - Khrabrov, Nikolai (Folder 10)
      - Russian Army Supply Commission, Washington (Folder 11)
        Available on microfilm reel 94
      - Russian Government Purchasing Commission, Washington (Folder 12)
      - Russian Supply Commmittee
        - General (Folder 13-14)
        - Agricultural Department (Box 82, Folder 1)
        - Anglo-Russian Subcommittee (Folder 2)
        - Artillery Commission
          - General
            - 1918
              - August (Folder 3)
              - September (Folder 4)
              - December (Folder 5)
            - 1918-1919 (Folder 6)
          - Metal Subdivision (Folder 7)
          - Rifle Subdivision
            - 1918 (Folder 8)
            - 1918-1919 (Folder 9)
          - Technical Bureau (Folder 10)
        - Chancery (Folder 11)
          Available on microfilm reel 95